<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Class &amp; Objects</title>
    <link>http://classandobjects.com/blogs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Class &amp; Objects</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 19:17:43 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://classandobjects.com/blogs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Level Up the Programming Skills : Language vs Logic</title>
      <link>http://classandobjects.com/blogs/level_up_programming_skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 19:17:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://classandobjects.com/blogs/level_up_programming_skills/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learning the language of computers can be both interesting and daunting. You may be either starting your career or are a seasoned developer, the chances are too likely that you are having trouble hitting the right balance between language and logical skills.  In this article, I will try to find out what is the right balance to keep levelling up our programming skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the current education system, most of the times, we tend to focus too much on the logical aspect of the programming. Understanding logic and different algorithms are albeit the most important part of programming. I believe that when you know why you are learning and what all can be done with your tools then you do it better and faster. Take an example of a man learning to be a carpenter. He is taught how to use the saw, hammer, nails, but he does not yet know how the hammer, nails and saw are related. The example may be poor but I hope you get the point. There is another extreme which mostly happen to the people from the non-computer background. They know how to code Java, Python and Ruby, but what they do not know is what are the tools that we have and how to use them efficiently. They do not understand things like time and space complexity or maybe they do, but after a long time. You can also find yourself in this situation if you are in the industry for a long while, where most of the work is easy. You get to learn new ways of doing things, new syntax and new technology, but you are not flexing your logical muscles much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a quick suggestion on what I feel is the right approach to the right balance. When you have plenty of time and you are in a learning phase, focus on building logic. You can build logical abilities by solving different algorithmic problems on different coding platforms. You should also try out classical problems like trees, sorting techniques, pattern printing and recursion. Now when you are comfortable with one language and know the logic, it is time to dive deep into learning language intricacies. Try getting your hands on some framework and build something real. The most obvious way would be to go with  web development or mobile development. You should also build some projects and start learning the language part(framework) when you are nearing to apply for a job. You need some solid projects to back you up in the interview. This is going to give you the matter to talk on and your logical skills are going to get you through the tricky programming questions most interviewers ask.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, I would just say that build your logical skills first and keep an eye on what are you going to do with these skills. As you get into the career you will not have much time to work on the logical part but you should keep taking some occasional coding challenges to keep yourself revitalized. Thanks for reading, looking forward to a difference in opinion!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Life: Work from home</title>
      <link>http://classandobjects.com/blogs/why_freelance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 23:11:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://classandobjects.com/blogs/why_freelance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I may be young, but age is just a number. I have seen life and work. I have been lost and I have been saved. I have travelled from the complete chaos of not knowing where to go and then to the bliss of understanding how everything fits together. I have hopped from language to language and now I understand them all(almost).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love to code in Python, given how clean, readable and maintainable it looks. In my professional work I use Ruby on Rails as my mode of transport and React js as my way to interact. I have always wondered how can one land a freelance job and then work less and enjoy more. I am a firm believer that workplace can never be as comfortable as home, the smell of my table, my fire(I&amp;rsquo;ll get one) and everything else. They just save you a lot of energy. You do not have to travel, time saved. You can use your resources and of course, earn better. I am also a budding traveller, I want to explore places and learn more, and of course, this includes technology. Freelancing empowers me in both the ways, financially and physically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.toptal.com/web&#34;&gt;Toptal&lt;/a&gt; is an awesome platform, indeed the best one for freelancing. If given, I would love to explore amazing people, exciting job and gorgeous lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Hugo is best for blogging? You should use it too!</title>
      <link>http://classandobjects.com/blogs/why_hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 19:45:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://classandobjects.com/blogs/why_hugo/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Just like any blogger, I also wanted to start my own blog. I had many doubts. What is my niche? Will people read my blog? Which platform to use for blogging? I do not know if I have found my answers, but for the last one it is &lt;strong&gt;HUGO&lt;/strong&gt;. Yes, I searched for different blogging platforms and all had their own set of drawbacks. Here are few reasons for not selecting them :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blogger : Free, SEO optimized, but no good themes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wordpress : Good themes, SEO Optimized, but costly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quora : Good theme, Free, but not SEO optimized&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would have used Wordpress, but I discovered &lt;strong&gt;HUGO&lt;/strong&gt;, which is times faster and way cheaper than Wordpress. Here I am on Hugo and doing amazing stuffs. Here are the reasons why I love Hugo:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fast-very-fast&#34;&gt;Fast, very fast&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did my research and found out that hugo is faster than Wordpress and many other products(static site generators) like Jekyll and Octopress2. You can see this &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/CdiDYZ51a2o&#34;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; on hugo official website and get the estimate. For detailed comparison, this &lt;a href=&#34;http://conscientiousprogrammer.com/blog/2015/05/31/why-i-switched-from-octopress-2-to-hugo/&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; is also an awesome resource.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In simple words, Hugo creates and stores your HTML file just once. This reduces the delay of creating HTML content every time. These files do not require much resource(CPU, Memory, etc), thus it can be hosted cheap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes-beautiful-themes&#34;&gt;Themes, beautiful themes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am crazy about the look and feel of anything. Say me nuts, but I will not use anything that does not look good. It may have lot of functionalities, but the feel is equally important to me. Hugo has a good set of themes you can choose from and customize, if needed. You can also create your own theme. This is also a theme called as &lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/crisp/&#34;&gt;Hugo Crips&lt;/a&gt;. I liked it for its simplicity. You can explore more hugo themes at &lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;themes.gohugo.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ease-of-setup&#34;&gt;Ease of Setup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!-- point about setup blog on ubuntu --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting up hugo is also really easy. They have setup files for most of the Operating system. You can find them &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/spf13/hugo/releases/tag/v0.15&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
You can just click and install it just like any other operating system. For ubuntu users they can download &lt;code&gt;hugo_0.15_amd64.deb&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;*.deb&lt;/code&gt; files depending on their platform. Then installing is just a matter of clicks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;host-for-free&#34;&gt;Host for free&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;!-- point about hosting github detailed blog --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is almost free to host them. They can be hosted for free on &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/tutorials/github-pages-blog/&#34;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/tutorials/hosting-on-bitbucket/&#34;&gt;bitbucket&lt;/a&gt; with links to their respective official tutorial. You can also see &lt;a href=&#34;http://classandobjects.com/hugo/host_static_site_on_github&#34;&gt;how to host a static website easily on github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A domain will cost you just $5 per year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;warning&#34;&gt;Warning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hugo has lots of features built-in, like &lt;code&gt;syntax highlighting&lt;/code&gt;, table of contents, pagination, etc. It has almost all the things you need for content development. If you want something more, you may have to wait or tinker around. Optimistically, you may create something which is missing and help the whole hugo community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you see &lt;strong&gt;Hugo is fast, beautiful, easy and free&lt;/strong&gt;. If you can take initial trouble of setting it up and getting is started, which is minimal, you are going to reap its benefits. Tough, you should remember hugo has just started its journey. So, awaken the hacker in you and get started&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>