<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reasons To Freelance on Class &amp; Objects</title>
    <link>http://classandobjects.com/tags/reasons-to-freelance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reasons To Freelance on Class &amp; Objects</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 23:11:40 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://classandobjects.com/tags/reasons-to-freelance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>To Life: Work from home</title>
      <link>http://classandobjects.com/blogs/why_freelance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 23:11:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://classandobjects.com/blogs/why_freelance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I may be young, but age is just a number. I have seen life and work. I have been lost and I have been saved. I have travelled from the complete chaos of not knowing where to go and then to the bliss of understanding how everything fits together. I have hopped from language to language and now I understand them all(almost).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love to code in Python, given how clean, readable and maintainable it looks. In my professional work I use Ruby on Rails as my mode of transport and React js as my way to interact. I have always wondered how can one land a freelance job and then work less and enjoy more. I am a firm believer that workplace can never be as comfortable as home, the smell of my table, my fire(I&amp;rsquo;ll get one) and everything else. They just save you a lot of energy. You do not have to travel, time saved. You can use your resources and of course, earn better. I am also a budding traveller, I want to explore places and learn more, and of course, this includes technology. Freelancing empowers me in both the ways, financially and physically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.toptal.com/web&#34;&gt;Toptal&lt;/a&gt; is an awesome platform, indeed the best one for freelancing. If given, I would love to explore amazing people, exciting job and gorgeous lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>